Guide to the Steel Industries Engineering Corporation Records, 1931-1938 AIS.1964.36
ULS Archives & Special Collections
Steel Industries Engineering Corporation Records
1931-1938
ULS Archives & Special Collections
Steel Industries Engineering Corporation
AIS.1964.36
3.125 Linear Feet (6 boxes)
The records of the Steel Industries Engineering Corporation include lists of officers and directors, memoranda on company dissolution, and correspondence of company heads.
Scope and Content Notes
This collection contains a list of officers and directors and memoranda on company dissolution. Included are the correspondence of chairman (Clifton Taylor), president (William Johnston, Jr.), vice-president (Jay W. Ferree), secretary (James G. Fulton), and treasurer (Ralph F. Leckey). The collection also contains company business correspondence with U.S. and foreign firms, financial records; business papers; legal papers; patents and patent information; specifications, photographs, information on products. The business papers and personal correspondence of William Johnston, Jr. are also included in the patent series.
Access Restrictions
No restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Charles E. Peterson, July 3, 1964.
Previous Citation
Steel Industries Engineering Corporation Records, 1931-1938, AIS.1964.36, Archives Service Center, University of Pittsburgh.
Business and Industry; Steel Industries Engineering Corporation
- Organization, I.
  - List of Officers, directors, etc. (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Voting Trust Agreement (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Memorandum concerning company dissolution, 1939 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Board of Directors, II.
  - Board of Directors, undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Chairman Clifton Taylor, III.
  - Correspondence, 1.
    - General, 1931-1933 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Higbee, T.S., 1931-1933 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Hopkins, J.C., 1931-1933 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Taylor, Aldrich, 1932 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Memoranda, 2.
    - General (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Expense memoranda, 1931-1933 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- President, William Johnson, Jr., IV.
  - Business Correspondence and Memoranda, 1.
    - Comstock, J.R., 1935, 1937 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Ferree, J.W., 1933 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Fulton, James G., 1932 1937-1938 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Galloway, Louis, 1933-1937 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Geesman, Wilbur H., 1932, 1935-1937 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Geet, Frank, 1937 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Hopkins, John C., 1939-1940 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Jackson, John E., 1937 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Lasher, Walter B., 1933 1937-1938 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Lehr, Charles E., 1937 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Osolin, Alfred, 1928-1936 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Taylor, Clifton, 1931-1936 (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - Miscellaneous, 1933-1941 (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - General (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - Clinton Taylor (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - Metal Mining Convention, Salt Lake City, Correspondence, notebook, notes, etc., 1939 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Personal Papers, 2.
    - Correspondence (Box 2, Folder 1-2)
    - Business Papers (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Business Records (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Bank statements, canceled checks (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Bills, invoices (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Legal papers (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - McConnellstown Farm (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Christmas, 1942-1943, 1946 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Thanksgiving, 1945 (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Vice President, Jay W. Ferree, V.
  - Correspondence, 1935, 1937-1938 (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Secretary, James G. Fulton, VI.
  - Correspondence, 1936-1939 (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Treasurer, Ralph F. Leckey, VII.
  - Correspondence, 1937 (Box 2, Folder 13)
- Steel Industries Engineering Corporation, VIII.
  - Miscellaneous Business Correspondence (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Algoma Steel Corporation, Pig Machine (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - American Chain and Cable Company, Inc. (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - American Flexible Coupling (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - ARMCO Culbert Manufacturers Association, Middletown, Ohio (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Ashmore Benson Pease and Company Stockton on Trees,England (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Bethlehem Steel Corporation, Lackawanna, New York (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Bethlehem Steel Corporation, Pittsburgh (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Bethlehem Steel Corporation, Sparrows Point, Maryland (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Bonney-Floyd Company, 1931-1933 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - A.W. Beyers Company, 1931 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Carnegie-Illinois Steel Corporation, Chicago, Illinois (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Carnegie-Illinois Steel Corporation, Gary Works, Pig Machine (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Carnegie-Illinois Steel Corporation, Mingo Junction, Ohio (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Carnegie-Illinois Steel Corporation, Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Carnegie-Illinois Steel Corporation, New Castle Works (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Chateaugay Ore and Iron Company (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Colorado Fuel and Iron Company, Pueblo, California (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Columbia Steel Company, Provo, Utah (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Dominion Steel and Coal Corporation, Sydney, Nova Scotia (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Ford Motor Company, Pig Casting Machinery (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Forney's (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Great Lakes Steel Corporation, Detroit, Michigan (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Great Lakes Steel Corporation, Clay Gun (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Great Lakes Steel Corporation, Green and MacCallister (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Inland Steel Company, Pig Casting Machine (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - International Harvester, Wisconsin Steel Works, 1934-1938 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Koninkeliike Nederlandsche Hogovens en Staalfabrieken N.V., Ijmuiden, Holland (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Arthur G. MacKee Company (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Mackintosh-Hemphill Company, Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Mississippi Valley Company, 1932 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - National Safety Council, Handling of hot slag and metal (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - National Slag Association (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Newton, Chambers and Company Ltd., Sheffield, England, 1937 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Osterreichisch-Alpone Motangesellschaft, Vienna, Austria, 1929-1931 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Pittsburgh Steel Foundry Corporation (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Reading Steel Casting Division of the Reading Pratt Cady Company, 1936-1937 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Republic Steel Corporation, Birmingham, Alabama (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Republic Steel Corporation, Cleveland, Ohio (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - H.H. Robertson Company, Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Tornblad and Lees, 1937-1938 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Weirton Steel Company, Weirton, West Virginia (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Wellman Engineering Company, Cleveland, Ohio (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Wheeling Steel Corporation, Clay Gun #2 Furnaces (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Business Papers (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Legal Papers (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Business Memoranda (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Financial Records, 1931, 1932-1933 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Bills and Invoices, 1933, 1938 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Stenographic Notebooks (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Lease (Rental) Empire Building Office (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Receipt for registered mail (Box 4, Folder 19)
- Patents, IX.
  - United States (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Canadian (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Patent Papers (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Patent Application of William Johnston Jr. re: Cinder Pot (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Patent History, Clay Gun (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Patent application for metalizing cinder pots, 1940 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Patents relating to magnesium (Box 5, Folder 4)
- Manufactured Products, X.
  - Cinder Pot Record (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Corrugated cinder pot (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Manipulators, skull puller, etc. (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Mud Gun Specifications (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Pig Casting Machine, General (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Pig Casting Machine, Photolithography (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Pig Casting Machine, Photographs (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Pig Casting Machine, Reports (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Pig Casting Machine, New Pig Machine Data (Box 6, Folder 4)
- Laboratory Reports, XI.
  - Laboratory Reports (Box 6, Folder 5)
- Drawings and Blueprints, XII.
  - Drawings and Blueprints (Box 6, Folder 6)
- Miscellaneous Industry Publications, XIII.
  - Industry Publications, Miscellaneous (Box 6, Folder 7)
- Salesman's Statements, 1927; XIV.
  - Salesman's Statements, 1927 (Box 6, Folder 8)